Alamin Rahman

Address: Romford, London

Mobile: 07539852381 Email: alamin7846@gmail.com

Portfolio: alaminrahman.co.uk

Personal Profile

I recently completed a Boot Camp in Software where I was able to hone my skills in HTML, Python, MySQL, CSS3 and JavaScript, combining experience in customer service and business operations.

Through my enrolment in the Software Development Skills Bootcamp with Just IT and ongoing self-study on platforms like Udemy and YouTube. This commitment reflects my dedication and eagerness to expand my knowledge in this field, aligning with my goal of becoming a skilled Junior Software Developer. I aim to create solutions that solve problems, continually learn and grow in coding and expand my horizons.

I offer versatility and reliability, understand the importance of delivering a high standard of customer care whilst providing a high standard of work, comfortable in demanding and fast-paced environments.

Core Skills

- Call Handling
- Customer Service
- Payment Processing
- Market Research
- Team Leading
- Microsoft Excel
- Organisational
- Time management
- Content Creation

IT Skills

Web Technology: HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript Technology: Git | GitHub

Education and IT Training

Web Development Bootcamp (Udemy)

(Ongoing)

- Software bootcamp covering languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, React, PostgreSQL, Web3 and DApps
- Fundamentals of Web Design, User Interface (UI) and User Experience (UX) Design

Click Start London - Digital Skills Training

(Nov 2023 - Dec 2023)

- Click Start is a programme based around essential digital skills relating to how to collect, manage and utilise data
- Fundamentals of Digital Marketing and Microsoft Office Specialist in Excel qualification
- Tech Adoption Lab paired with a Small/Medium Employer (SME) supporting the SME to adopt a new technology. The aim is to supplement classroom training with real business examples and learn the consultative skills that enable me to really embed my tech skills and develop the skills for work.

Just IT Training - Software Development Bootcamp

(June 2023 - Sep 2023)

• A twelve-week intensive bootcamp covering the fundamentals of Web and Software development such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL and Python

Canterbury College - Diploma

(Sep 2017 - May 2019)

Plumbing diploma level 2 & 3

Darul Uloom London - GCSE's and Diploma

(Jan 2011 - Oct 2017)

Completed GCSE's and Level 2 Team Leading Diploma

Coding Projects

JavaScript:

• Created a weather app, text to speech app and a guiz game.

Python and MySQL:

Created a <u>movie database</u> with CRUD functionality.

Ongoing:

Currently working on my next project

Employment History

India Royal - Waiter/Manager

(Jun 2015 - Aug 2023)

- Waiter (2015-2020), Manager (2020-2023)
- Demonstrated flexibility and adaptability by taking on more responsibilities as manager such as, managing the business, dealing with complaints, paying wages, ordering stock, etc.
- Used time management and organisation to help with processing customer orders to help keep the flow moving
- Provided excellent customer service skills by handling customer requests and complaints in a prompt manner during busy hours.
- Dealt with inventory and end of day takings.

Personalise Me Ltd - Social Media Manager

(Oct 2021 - March 2022)

- Demonstrated strong organisational and time management skills by handling projects and deadlines within set period.
- Effectively utilised market research and content creation to help enhance social media presence and gain new traffic to the page.
- Collaborated with colleagues to help create and manage content calendar and social media pages as well as run an e-commerce business through Shopify
- Helped improve client brand identities and content strategies by reviewing and providing feedback to social media pages.
- Regularly posted and updated social media posts

Lazard Plumbing - Apprentice Plumber

(Sep 2019 - March 2020)

- Addressed customer inquiries through written and verbal communication while assisting colleagues.
- Worked effectively in a team environment and individually when needed.
- Demonstrated flexibility and adaptability while utilising various tools and equipment which helped with troubleshooting and problem-solving where needed.

Interests

Hobbies: Gaming | Gym | Reading | Continuous learning | Movies/TV

Additional Info:

- I have a full driving licence
- I speak both English and Bengali

References available upon request